The Story of Nian
年的故事
In the old days, there was a monster, it was Nian.
在古时候  有一只叫年的猛兽
Everyone was afraid of it.
大家都很怕它
Spring was coming.
春天来了
Nina went to a village at night,it ate many animals.
年在夜里去到一个农庄  吃了很多动物
One day, an old man came to the village,
有一天  一位老者来到村庄
“Don’t be afraid, I have an idea.” he said.
他说道   别害怕  我有个主意
He put a couplet on the door and set off fireworks.
他在门上贴了对联  并燃放鞭炮
People followed him.
人们也都一一效仿
Nina came again,it saw the red couplets and heard the fireworks,
年又来了  它看到了红色的对联  又听到了鞭炮的声音
it was afraid and ran away.
它害怕了  然后就逃走了
Everyone was happy again.
大家又开心了起来
From then on,
从那时候开始
they put up couplets and set off fireworks on that day every year.
人们在每年的那天都会贴对联 放鞭炮
The day was named Nian.
那一天就叫做年